Preliminary Guide to the Robert Kendall Papers, 1990-2010
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Robert Kendall papers 1990-2010
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Kendall, Robert.
12.0 linear feet Extent: 5000 Items
Hypertext poet and author; member of the Electronic Literature Organization. Collection includes Kendall's electronic equipment, manuscript drafts of his poetry, and electronic media of published and unpublished poems by Kendall and other hypertext authors. The majority of this collection is closed to research until use copies of electronic media can be made.
RL.00799
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is restricted. Electronic media and files are closed until use copies can be made. Also, no publication of any portion of the email correspondence in the collection is allowed without the written permission of the Donor (for emails written by the Donor) or the writer of the email (for emails sent to the Donor).
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Robert Kendall Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2012.
Historical Note
Robert Kendall has been creating interactive multimedia poetry since 1990, making him one of the earliest practitioners of the form. He is the author of a book-length hypertext poem, A Life Set for Two (Eastgate Systems, 1996). His hypertext poetry has also appeared on disk in The Little Magazine and Version Box and is forthcoming in the anthology Behind the Lines (Eastgate). It has appeared on the Web at Iowa Review Web, BBC Online, Eastgate Hypertext Reading Room, Cauldron & Net, and Cortland Review. A Wandering City (Cleveland State University Poetry Center, 1992), his printed book of poems, won the CSU Poetry Center Prize. Kendall's printed poetry has appeared widely in magazines (including Rattapallax, Contact II, River Styx, New York Quarterly, Barrow Street, and Indiana Review), and several anthologies have included his work. He has received a New Jersey State Council on the Arts Fellowship for Literature and a New Forms Regional Grant Program Award.
(Excerpted from Kendall's homepage, http://www.wordcircuits.com/kendall/bio.htm)
Collection Overview
Collection includes Kendall's early computers, hard drives, and electronic media, as well as drafts and versions of his writings in paper and electronic formats. Manuscript portion of the collection includes paper drafts of his electronic and print poems and short stories. Also includes software and hardware manuals used to create e-poetry, and electronic publications by other authors, collected by Kendall. The majority of this collection is closed to research until use copies of electronic media can be made.
Subject Headings
Kendall, Robert; Electronic Literature Organization; Hypertext poetry; Poetry, Modern -- 20th century; Poetry -- 21st century
Contents of Collection
- Papers and Electronic Media, 1990s-2000s, (5 boxes)
  Drafts of Kendall's writings and poetry, including both paper and electronic formats, as well as copies of electronically published writings by other hypertext and digital authors.
  [Original versions of electronic records are closed to use. To request access, please contact a reference archivist before coming to use this collection.]
  - Paper drafts of poetry (Box 1)
    - Drafts of electronic poems (Box 1)
      Drafts for the following electronic poems. The drafts for Faith reveal the working process for creating the "layered" structure of verses unique to this poem: exploring alternatives for early layers by circling different combinations of words in the final layer. The drafts for After Closing utilize pages of paper cut into strips and stapled together in the manner of Queneau's "Cent Mille Milliards de Poèmes."
      - It All Comes Down to _____ (SoftPoem) (Box 1)
      - After Closing (Unpublished) (Box 1)
      - Framework (Box 1)
      - Two Duets (Box 1)
      - Dispossession (Box 1)
      - Penetration (Box 1)
      - Clues (Box 1)
      - Faith (Box 1)
      - In the Garden of Recounting (Box 1)
      - Candles for a Street Corner (Box 1)
      - Paper Music, Ear Ink (Box 1)
      - The Visitation of St. America (work in progress, started in 1997) (Box 1)
      - Life Story (work in progress; print version entitled "You're Waiting for It to Ring the Bell?") (Box 1)
    - Drafts for Logozoa texts (Box 1)
  - Drafts for print poems (Box 2)
    Drafts for poems intended for a second book of print poems that is unpublished. Paper drafts for "A Life Set for Two" and drafts for printed book "A Wandering City." Among the latter are also drafts of early poems that were not included in the book.
  - Drafts for print poems: A Wandering City (Box 3)
  - Software used to create e-poetry (Box 3)
  - Hardware manuals (Box 3)
  - Videos (The Clue: A MiniMystery) (Box 3)
  - Eastgate Systems Publications (Box 3)
  - 3.5" diskettes (Box 4)
    Includes works by individual authors, magazines and collections, and literary authoring systems. All disks require migration to the library servers before researchers can access the material.
  - 5.25" diskettes (Box 4)
  - Packaged works on 3.5" diskettes (Box 4)
  - Storyspace manuals and installation disks (Box 4)
  - CD-ROMs (Box 4)
  - Windows 3.0 (Box 4)
  - Publications by Kendall, on disk (Box 5)
    - A Wandering City (Box 5)
    - A Life Set for Two (Box 5)
    - Electronic Literature Collection on CD (Box 5)
    - Black Swan Review's special issue "Illiterature," co-edited by Kendall (Box 5)
    - WriteTrak disks (Box 5)
  - Version Box (Box 5)
    This box contains various works of physical artwork, along with copies of "The Clue: A MiniMystery" and 3 works of e-poetry by French authors on floppy disk. The French authors are Philippe Bootz, Jean Louis Boissier, and Michel Butor. This collection was assembled as part of the Version 2.2 Festival in Geneva, Switzerland, held in 1996. Kendall participated in the festival, reading "The Clue."
  - Brochures and programs related to Kendall's e-poetry (Box 5)
  - Unpublished works (Box 5)
    Includes short stories, poetry, and publication software for Eastgate Systems.
  - Personal correspondence, 1992-1996 (Box 6)
  - Published articles (Box 6)
  - Drafts of A Wandering City, other poems, (2 folders) (Box 6)
  - Publicity and reviews (Box 6)
  - Bound volumes of published works, 1984-1986 (Box 6)
  - Bound volumes of published works, 1986-1993 (Box 7)
  - Bound volumes of published works, 1985-2002 (Box 8)
- Electronic Equipment, (6 boxes)
  Computers, monitors, and speakers used for installations of Kendall's work in the 1990s. These materials are currently being evaluated for their content and are closed pending processing.
  - Computers and hardware (Box 9-14)
    [Closed pending review.]